

CONTACT



+31 644 147 968



mihai.mijea.dev@gmail.com



mihaiyoo6



in/mihaimijea



Amsterdam, The Netherlands

SKILLS

| JAVASCRIPT | 7 years |
|----------------|---------|
| HTML/CSS | 7 years |
| REACT JS | 4 years |
| SCSS/JS-IN-CSS | 4 years |
| NODE JS | 4 years |
| REST API | 4 years |
| MICROSERVICE | 3 years |
| MONGO DB | 2 years |
| CI/CD | 3 years |
| DOCKER | 3 years |

EDUCATION

MASTER DEGREE ELECTRONIC AND COMMUNICATION INTEGRATED SYSTEMS

Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science 2012 - 2014 | UNITBV

BACHELOR'S DEGREE TELECOMMUNICATIONS TECHNOLOGIES AND SYSTEMS

Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science 2008 - 2012 | UNITBV

MIHAI MIJEA

SENIOR FULL-STACK DEVELOPER | CONTRACTOR | FREELANCER

ABOUT ME

I'm Senior Javascript FullStack Developer / Contractor / Freelancer with **7+ years of experience** in building web applications, only interested in remote work. I help companies around the world to design and implement their software solutions.

Drop me a message if you think my expertise could help your organization!

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR REACTJS/NEXTJS JAVASCRIPT ENGINEER

Aug 2021 - present

DPG Media | interim via PassionatePeople

DPG Media Group is a Belgian media company also active in the Netherlands and Denmark, was facing difficulties with the current way of onboarding new and managing existing media website

- Reduced the time to onboard new brands 30%, by designing a modular and distributed platform
- Increased the overall website performance by 50%, by implementing a static site generation solution
- Increased the site ranking by 25%, by implementing all SEO best practices

Skills: ReactJS, NextJS, Taiwlind, Microservices, Swagger OpenAPI specification, UnitTest Jest

SOFTWARE ENGINEER CONSULTANT

Aug 2019 - present

PassionatePeople

Passionate People is a software consultancy company focused on leading and developing world-class web applications.

Being part of this family gives me the opportunity to help clients across the Netherlands, helping them grow their businesses, by joining their teams and high-quality solutions.

SENIOR JAVASCRIPT FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Jan 2021 - Aug 2021

KPN | interim via PassionatePeople

The client a Dutch landline and mobile telecommunications company was having difficulties with its current web components and layouts to be able to integrate new features on the website and enable a personalization system.

- Reduced time to 30%, by redesigning old layouts to be easier to add content and personalize the
 content.
- Dramatically reduced the customer care calls by 40% over a month period, by integrating chat options for the troubleshooting page on the website.

Skills: VueJs, AngularJs, SCSS/SASS, PatternLab, JQuery, Bootstrap, Scrum/Agile/Jira, Git/GitLab.

SENIOR BACKEND JAVSCRIPT DEVELOPER

Aug 2020 - Nov 2020

IceMobile | interim via PassionatePeople

The client, a big russian retailer, was struggling with the native mobile application stability, due to the data inconsistency caused by having the data spread in multiple systems.

- Eliminated the data inconsistency by dropping the number of data related **errors to 0** by designing an aggregation layer for processing and enriching the data to be fed as proper input in the application.
- Increased the application downloads/installation by 10%, by decreasing average response time with 25%, by implementing a caching layer.

Skills: NodeJS, ExpressJS, Swagger OpenAPI specification, UnitTest Jest

SENIOR JAVASCRIPT FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Sep 2019 - Aug 2020

Rodeo - Make it Flow | interim via PassionatePeople

The client who was in the middle of developing a subscription based all-in-one project management software was facing multiple issues due the fact that the application was not scalable, hard to release, the development cycle was long, and the key features as the generation of PDFs and subscription system were having bugs generating clients complaints.

- Drastically increased the development **speed by 50%**, by designing a reusable UI components library bringing a more consistent look and feel of the application.
- Drastically reduced the time to **generate and preview PDFs by 80%**, by designing a highly available microservice to handle the PDF requests.
- Reduced the **number of wrong calculated subscriptions to 0** by researching and integrating to a third party service which was specialised in subscription models
- Reduced time to market **from 2 weeks to 1h** by designing and implementing a fully automated release process that could be triggered by any team member.
- Increased the **SLA to 99.9**% by migrating the database and the storage to cloud solution, leading also a gain of **average request response by 5**%.

Skills: ReactJS (Material-ui), React-Pdf, feathersJS, styled-components, story-book, atomic-design, GitLab CI/CD, GIT,Google Cloud(App Engine), MongoDb - Atlas Mongo., Microservices, OpenAPI swagger spec, Unittest jest, Chargebee SDK.

SENIOR FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Sep 2018 - Aug 2019

Fonterm Ventures B.V. | fontemventures.com

The client, a company selling e cigarettes, was experiencing difficulties in creating and updating content on the online platform due to the current content management system being slow and difficult.

 Decreased the time to market from 2 days to 3 minutes by providing an automated content delivvery pipeline, by designing highly scalable and reusable content-model on top of Contentful headless api CMS and implementing a reusable UI components library to match the content-model, providing lego like possibilities to the content editors for creating customised experiences

Skills: ReactJS, styled-components, Storybook, Gatsby, GraphQL, unit-test Jest, netlifyAPI, Contentful SDK, Contenful content model, CI/CD.

SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Jan 2015 - Sep 2018

SuitSupply | suitsupply.com

The client, a global manufacturer of high quality suits, was looking to offer its clients the in-store experience of creating unique garment pieces with the guidance of a tailor, but in an online medium, in order for customers to be able to create custom pieces from the comfort of their homes.

- Increased the **revenue by 15**% by designing a modular web interface that could be accessed by both in-store tailors to assist clients needs on site and by at home customers through the e-commerce platform.
- Increased **user engagement 50%** by engineering a custom system for rendering the visual representation of the custom garment, as there were hundreds of combinations,

Skills: Responsive Design, Handlebars, SCSS, NodeJS, HapiJS, RestAPI, Cloudinary Image delivery